

About

With experience spanning strategic roles in large corporations, a scale-up, and a start-up, I am keen to play an active role in accelerating a company's growth.

- 06 21 42 72 21
- dechazeauxb@gmail.com
- ? 1 rue Fénelon, 75010 PARIS

Education

Audencia Business School

Master in Management (Grande Ecole) 2014 - 2017

Université Paris 1 Panthéon Sorbonne

Master 1 - Economy 2009 - 2013

Tools

- Business Intelligence (Tableau)
- CRM (Salesforce)
- No code tools (Notion, Miro, Airtable, Cycle, Bubble...)
- SQL
- Office suite (Powerpoint, Excel)

BENJAMIN **DE CHAZEAUX**

Strategy & Go-to-Market

Experience

Go-to-Market Manager

2022 - Current

Opendatasoft (Data Portal - SaaS - B2B)

- **Identifying New Opportunities:** Conducted comprehensive market analysis and strategic opportunity assessments, developed business cases, prioritized key opportunities, and defined associated value propositions, translating them into actionable Product & Service offerings.
- Translating into Product & Service Offerings: Led data-driven analyses to define target personas, identify key pain points, and develop tailored solutions leveraging Opendatasoft's capabilities.
- **Defining related Commercial Strategy:** Coordinated the launch of various offerings and the new market positioning, collaborating closely with Marketing and Sales teams. Defined OKRs and oversaw campaign execution across multiple channels.
- **Financial Optimization:** Evaluated and refined pricing strategies to drive optimal financial performance.

Strategic Project Manager

2021 - 2022

Leboncoin

- Market Analysis: Conducting an in-depth analysis of the automotive segment to inform strategic decisions and future investments.
- **Technology Vision:** Developing a 3-year Tech strategy that aligns technological innovations with the company's long-term objectives.
- Performance Optimization: Managing the annual review of OKRs (Objectives and Key Results) to enhance performance.
- Commercial Transformation: Leading the change in business model for the marketplace.
- **Customer Service Improvement:** Auditing and implementing strategic recommendations to enhance customer service.
- Post Merger Integration: Overseeing the integration of acquired companies.

Strategy Senior Consultant

2020 - 2021

Wavestone (ex - Kurt Salmon part of Accenture Strategy)

Engagement missions on strategic and organizational topics such as:

- Leading budget planning and headcount management (France #1 e-commerce platform)
- Developing direct distribution strategy across Europe and Africa Telecom industry (>25 countries)
- Defining marketing strategy for new services business unit Leading service provider in France
- Conducting market research on e-commerce adoption by SMEs & developed Go-to-Market strategy – Leading service provider in France
- Analyzing risks and impacts of digital transformation for the #1 global retailer (14,000 stores in over 40 countries)
- Assessing budgetary and organizational impact of digitizing operations for the #1 French media group